Friends, at the time of payment of 5 years health insurance premium, the
health insurance claim was
rejected. Why did this happen? What was the mistake? Was it the
insurance company's mistake? Was it the
individual's mistake? Or was it the hospital's
mistake? Today we will discuss this in detail. But
today we will also talk about how you can get the
best health insurance plan for yourself, your family, your mother.
Who does it? Therefore,
I will do the best health insurance plan. Will
your insurance company do it or will an
insurance advisor do it? No, friends, you
can do it yourself. You can check yourself sitting at home
which company is the best for you and
your family for health
insurance. Let's start today's
video. If you have
n't subscribed to our channel yet, then do
subscribe. My
name is Ashish Singh Rawat. Insurance Advice is
definitely here. We share with you information ranging from small to big, from life insurance to help
insurance to motor insurance, for
yourself, for children, for family, for
parents. So friends, here below,
I and my team have
provided our services to more than 5000 people and have
helped many people in claim settlement. If you too  If you
want to port your health insurance plan or buy a
new one,
our team will definitely help you. Friends,
today we're going to discuss the topic
I mentioned: how you
can plan your own health insurance.
Before that, it's important to understand why
people do
n't buy health insurance when it comes to health insurance.
Friends, currently,
only 25% of people in India have a
proper health insurance plan. 75% of people
still don't know about it, or they do
n't
want to get into it. Friends, there are three reasons why
people don't buy health insurance. The
first is that they say, "I'm
young, I don't need it now." The second reason is
that someone close to them, or a
family member or friend, has paid the insurance
premium, but
their insurance is rejected when they're admitted to the hospital. The
third reason could be that
friends, we don't actually know
how health insurance works and what its
benefits are. So,
in this video, I'll discuss why you should buy health insurance
or what its benefits might be.
How can you get the best health insurance plan for yourself,
from where can you check the best claim settlement,
we are going to
give all this information in this video today, so do
watch the video till the end and in the end, do
tell me how you liked the video.
Friends, here a person starts
earning money in his youth, he feels that he
is young and he will not face any health challenge yet,
so let me tell you one thing here that
like Covid, stone, appendix,
viral infection, type 2 AIDS, malaria, all these
diseases do not come by looking at any age,
you start saving from the age of 25, you start saving from
10, you save 10-15 lakhs,
God forbid, such a
situation arises that you have to get admitted in a hostel
and the savings you have made will have to be broken, it is
better than this, I say,
no brother, do not take your health for granted,
brother, you have to
deposit some amount every month
so that
you will have a very good policy, it is a very
good thing, but when any family
member has to pay for the hostel,
but the people who are with you
in the hospital  You are going, you are getting it, you are
not going to your work, brother,
who will recover their physical loss, mental loss, it is a
matter of sleep, friends, let's
start the video, friends, first of all, when we go to get
health insulin, then many times it happens that
we already have insurance for our already existing condition for
which we are undergoing treatment, then that is
called free existing
disease, yes friends, keep
this thing in mind which you already have before taking health insulin,
it is called pre-existing
disease, whenever you go to get this health insurance
plan, you will get a verification call from whichever company
you have to
tell there that brother, I have asthma, I have
diabetes, I have BP problem, you have to make
this thing clear that brother, I am going to have an
operation in the near future, there will be
two things, either the company will
not give you insurance, okay, now if you are not given insurance,
it does not mean that you have suffered a loss,
friends, here they will tell you in advance,
you pay this much premium, after that they will
tell you even before your screen is rejected,
now you cannot get medical insurance in this condition,
diseases
like asthma  For diabetics,
you can add add-on services to your insurance plan, due to
which they will increase the premium,
but they will also provide you with a help insurance plan. There is a
waiting period for these.
Some companies have a waiting period of 3 years, some have 2 years, some have 1
year, but
most companies have a minimum waiting period of 2 years.
So this waiting period
is very less, friends, when this waiting period is
over, all your diseases will be cured. You have to
talk keeping both period and pre-existing diseases in mind when
you take this insurance plan. If you have
hidden any of them and it comes to light tomorrow, then your
insurance will be rejected. No, suppose
your child is 5 years old now,
after five years he will be 10 years old.
If you say that my child
is 7 years old even after five years, then
who will believe it? Even the doctor knows
which disease has been going on for a very long time. So
friends, you have to keep this thing in mind.
Friends, the second point to keep in mind for getting the best health insurance plan is that  It is
that your health
insurance is not being taken care of, see there are many
people who are not able to take health insurance
plan because they do not have the need,
they are not insured, it is a very good
thing that they are not insured, but what happens
when you are not able to insure your health,
here you are given the facility of no flame bonus or
registration
restoration, meaning if you do not do it this year then
you will get a discount in the premiums for the next year
or you will be given a big boost,
now there can be two-two or three
types of add-ons here, suppose
here you bought a plane of Rs 10 lakh,
okay, if you do not do it here, then
next year also you will get Rs 10 lakh, next year also you will get Rs
10 lakh, even after two-three years, but there are
some companies which have
given advanced services, here they
give you registration benefit, here you have
bought a plane of Rs 10 lakh, you have not claimed for one year yet, for
2 years the amount of Rs 10 lakh will be
more, that is, it will become Rs 20 lakh, if you do
not do it for 3 years then it will become Rs 30 lakh,
for Rs 400 it will become Rs 40 lakh  So keep the
company in mind like this. You should keep the second point in mind.
I will talk about the third point.
Friends, today technology has
advanced. We don't need to be admitted for 24 hours
because the
insurance company's claim is given only when it closes.
From 24 to 48 hours, at least you will have to be admitted for 48 hours.
But now, the
treatment unit has started today. Where
if your treatment is only for one to two hours,
you will get your film there. Yes,
friends, this is a very good thing. Many
companies provide this hospitality
under their insurance plan. Please keep this thing in
mind. Talking about the fourth point,
friends, there is free and forced hostel.
Many
companies provide this facility under the treatment that I told you about here.
What does this mean? See,
in any card you are admitted to the hospital, all
your expenses incurred 60 days before that will be refunded to you. All the
expenses for the 120 days after discharge will be
refunded to you. Friends, keep this thing in
mind, friends, this option is in your health
insurance.  It is very important to be within the claim,
friends, let's talk about point number five.
Here, people often say, friend, should I take an
individual plan or a family plan,
because this family photo plan was done.
Suppose you have taken a sum insured of Rs 10 lakh, then it is
for all the four-five of you and all the members of the family,
and friends, it never happens that all
five of the family members get admitted at the same time.
Friends, if you are not single and belong to a family, then do the
family tutor plan only, in that
you also
get a discount of up to 30% on the family photo plan. Point
number six is, friends, entry forward, that is,
what is your entry forward, see, 18 years, 22
years entry is your policy,
but the most important is the exit forward. Some
companies do not provide health insurance after 10 years, not
less, after 70 years.
Some companies provide it for 100 years,
so definitely choose this thing within your policy.
This one point
is very important because right now we are young,
but we will reach the category of just scenery citizens due to
illness.  And the second flood will come
friends, point number 7 is that see,
every company's plans have different
benefits, yes, the company's benefits will be
more, you have to pay that as per the company,
many times what happens is that we
ignore a little more
and do not take this policy, it
is expensive, but you must look at its benefits, are
they giving you more benefits,
friends, the eighth point is, in the
policies that were there in these old times, health
insurance policies, it used to be that suppose there was a
bill of 10 lakhs, out of which
you had to pay 2 lakhs, the company used to pay 8 lakhs,
but in the asking date, almost all the
companies have abolished it, the copayment has been
removed from everywhere, in things like room rent or
ambulance charges or the
capping that used to be there in ambulance charges has been done,
whenever you look at the policy, you
will see what is your sum injured, how much are you getting
in 5 lakhs and ambulance
charges, how much are you getting in 10 lakhs, any of
your plans.  You
should not go camping, which means you should
not spend any money from there. This is called
no payment. Friends, if we talk about point number nine, then there is a
big game of network hospitals here. The company says that I have
500 hospitals in my network, I have
400 or 800 hospitals in my network, but you should
not go towards that. If you live in an area, you
can visit the nearest hospital once, then check which
help the company has in its tyres. If you
go to an emergency, you
can take it from any company. It is a very
simple thing. Point number 10.
You have a corporate health insurance corporation of the
company. It is a very
good thing for the family, but keep in mind that there are
copayments in it as well. After one over,
when you switch companies,
that insurance goes away from there.
Then when you join a new place, the
company will give it to you from there. So, you
can definitely claim on it tomorrow. Here,
many people make this mistake. They keep
relying on the company and there is
also camping there. But what should you do if you do not take the
health insurance of the company also.  Plainly you are doing it, do it
but along with it a
small five black and a healthy one for the legs
because it takes you 2 to 3 years to get rid of all the
diseases, so if
you take that opportunity now at a young age,
then your premium will also be less. Point number
11 is for claim settlement ratio, you have to
login on Google, you can
check the health insurance claim settlement ratio of IRDA, there
you will get to know the settlement ratio of all the companies, there you will get to know
what percentage is of which company. Point
number 10 Free medical checkup, friends, it is
very important to have a free health medical checkup every year in your health policy,
you should check this thing also. Point
number 13, friends, here we are talking about discount, the
company gives discount on 2 years premium and 3 years
premium, many
companies give this, if you can afford it, you
can give it, along with this you
can get discount when you live a healthy lifestyle,
friends, there are
apps of many companies, they say that
if you follow some steps then there
But you are given a discount of up to 30%.
Whichever company you are associated with or are going to
join,
please check in its application. There, if you
keep yourself active and physically fit, walk daily, take a
good walk, then you can
get the benefit of discount there.
14. Within the application itself, there
is ambulance and ambulance charges and find out
how many charges you are given under the insurance. You have to pay
those charges
yourself or the
company pays it. If you have paid, then will the
investment company give you or not?
Please check in that section.
Friends, these are some points where
you can choose the best health insurance plan for yourself.
Neither my help is necessary nor the
insurance company's help is necessary nor any
advisor's help is necessary. All these topics,
you should note down all these points. If you
want all these points in your health insurance policy, then there are many
advanced services here too, in which you
get more benefits, the sum insured increases and the
policy amount increases.  There are
many companies, in the next video we
will tell you how Aditya Birla does it
and we have already
compared three health insurance companies and
told you about it. I will give the link in the i button here,
you can get the link in the description below.
And friends, here if you
want to know specifically about Aditya Birla's company,
how it works, then I will give the link in the i button here
in the description below.
Friends, if you
want to take health advice for parents, then what
things to keep in mind, watch a special video, there is a
link there, there is a
link in the description below. Friends, here
I have tried to explain all the things to you and make
you comfortable. There are still many
points here, they have been covered further gradually.
Don't forget to subscribe to our channel to connect with such information. Friends,
if you are not happy with your health insurance company,
want to port it or
want to take a new plan, then friends,
contact us or you
can also mail us on our email ID. Our
team will contact you very soon.  It will do this and will
help you in solving whatever problem you have.
Friends, that's all for today, see you
in the next video.